Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 23, 1785; B F113; 8-3/4x7; La Blancherie, [Flammès Claude Catherine Pahin Champlain de], 1752-1811.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends him a notice that he is to begin a trip, and asks him to translate it into Italian and have it printed in the papers. For notes,see Concerning M.de La Blancherie; [July 23, 1785].
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence., B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; La Métherie, J[ean] C[laude] de, 1743-1817
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Maclure and friend.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; La Métherie, J[ean] C[laude] de, 1743-1817
    Florence. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Sobalewski.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 24, 1805; B F113; 9x7-1/2; La Métherie, J[ean] C[laude] de, 1743-1817.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication by Darcet, fils. Hopes he will distribute Journal de physique in Italy.
  - Letter to [Filippo] Mazzei, May 30, 1783; B F113; 7-3/4x6; La Rochefoucauld[-Liancourt, Francois Alexandre Frédéric, duc] de, 1747-1827.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Death of his father keeps him busy. Wishes him a happy return to America.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Oct. 19, 1808; B F113; 12-1/2x8-1/4; Lacépède, [Bernard Germain Etienne de la Ville, comte], 1756-1825.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Aug. 2, 1809; B F113; 12-1/2x8; Lacépède, [Bernard Germian Etienne de la Ville, comte], 1756-1825.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is made member of the cors-Legislatif.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, Jan. 17, 1799; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Lacépède, Bernard Germain Etienne de la Ville, comte, 1756-1825.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Farbroni papers.) Asks him to forward letter to Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Paris, March 2, 1810; B F113; 8x6; Lafayette, [Marie Jean Paul Joseph Roch Yves Gilbert de Motier, marquis de,] 1757-1834.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will see him while he is in Paris. Refers to Mazzei.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 16, 1801; B F113; 8x5-1/2; Lalande, [Joseph Jérome Le Français de], 1732-1807.
    Paris, A.L. in 3rd.p. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Returns manuscript.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, March 21, 1799; B F113; 6x4; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme le Français de], 1732-1807.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning eclipses noted in Florence.
  - Note to [Francesco] Favi, May 22, 1783; B F113; 2-1/4x3-1/4; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme Le Français de], 1732-1807.
    A.N.S. 1p.on back of playing card. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for list of Florentine authors.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]., B F113; 7x6-1/2; Lalande, [Joseph Jéróme Le Français] de, 1732-1807.
    L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces, and recommends, Panckoucke.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 24, 1801; B F113; 6-1/4x4; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme Le Français] de, 1732-1807.
    Paris A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning astronomical observations in Florence and wishes to be informed of them.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 16, 1801; B F113; 9-3/4x8; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme Le Français] de, 1732-1807.
    L. 2p. Copy. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the establishment of an observatory in Florence. Thanks for books Weights and measures.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 1, 1804; B F113; 8x4-3/4; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme Le Français] de, 1732-1807.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Preparations for eclipse. Refers to cost of instruments.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni, B F113; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Lalande, [Joseph Jérôme Le Français] de, 1732-1807.
    Florence. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning lunar eclipses, observed in Florence during the 14th Century.
  - Letter to [Jean Jacques Antoine] Caussin [de Perceval], July 23, [1799]; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Laplace, [Pierre Simon, marquis de], 1749-1827.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks that he place the Greek manuscript in the hands of Fabroni for return to Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 24, 1818; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Laplace, [Pierre Simon, marquis de], 1749-1827.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication. Weights and measures in Tuscany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 1, 1820; B F113; 7x4-1/2; Laplace, [Pierre Simon, marquis de], 1749-1827.
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards essay by Brongniart.
  - Letter to [Signora Teresa Fabroni]., B F113; 3-3/4x4-1/4; Laplace, Courty
    A.L.S. 2p. Fragment. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, Dec. 4, 1809; B F113; 7x4-3/4; Laplace, Mme Comtess
    Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, Dec. 19, 1809; B F113; 7x4-3/4; Laplace, MME Comtess
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 8-1/4x5; Lasteyrie[-Dusaillant, Charles Philibert, comte] de, 1759-1849.
    Sunday morning. A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks favor.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 12, 1802; B F113; 7-3/4x6; Lavoisier, [Marie Anne (Paulze)?], 1756-1836.
    L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes to hear from him and his family. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 28, 1792; B F113; 7x4-1/2; Le Brun, M[arie] L[ouise] E[lisabeth Vigée], 1755-1842.
    Vienne, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni Papers.) Concerning her portrait hanging in the ducal gallery.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 12, 1808; B F113; 10x8; Libri, G[uglielmo
    L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes to visit him and meet him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabrony, Florence, B F113; 8x4-3/4; Libri, G[uglielmo
    Dimanche [Sunday]. L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is delighted they will meet.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, March 23, 1781; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; M[azzei], F[ilippo], 1730-1816.
    Leghorn, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers Family affairs. Concerning his wife.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 5, 1794; B F113.m; 10x7-3/4; M[azzei], F[ilippo], 1730-1816.
    Pisa, A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Dec. 29, 1806; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; M[azzei], F[ilippo], 1730-1816.
    Pisa, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 20, 1780; B F113; 8x6-1/2; Magalhães, João Jacinto de, 1722-1790
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Current scientific events. Magnesium. Refers to John Fothergill, the Royal Society, James Watt, Joseph Priestley, Richard Kirwan and Benjamin Vaughan.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 17, 1787; B F113; 8x6-1/2; Magellan, J[ean] H[yacinth] de, 1723-1790.
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning shipments, and refers to Kirwan, the Royal Dublin Society, Maty, and the Lavoisier-phlogiston controversy.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct., 1812; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Magherini, G
    Florence, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Money matters.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 7, 1795; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Malachowski, Stanislas, Count, 1735-1809.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks him for his kindnesses and will always remember his visit to Florence. Returns to Russia.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 8, 1808; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Maret, Hugues B[ernard], 1763-1839.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces and recommends M.de Reuilles
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 31, 1781; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Mari, Cosimo
    Pisa, A.L.S. 4p.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Signora Mazzei. Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni;], 1780; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends him an account of the eruption of Etna.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 3, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning askes of sulphides.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 26, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Geography of the Cape of Angora.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, May 2, 1788; B F113; 9x8; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the geographical society.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 2, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning mineralogy and natural history.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 5, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning agricultural publications.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, May 30, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany and mineralogy.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, May 31, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Tarnowsky.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 2, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Tarnowsky and speaks of him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 16, 1788; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the analysis of water.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 14, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning sulphur.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 25, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Medical qualities of bathing.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 22, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the ship for the natural history museum.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 3, 1788; B F113; 8x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning black glass (obsidian?).
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 13, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a branch of medicine.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 2, 1789; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning coal.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 7, 1789; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Mariti, G[iovanni], 1736-1806.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 16, 1781; B F113; 12x8-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning lava and pumice from the eruption of Etna.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Oct. 6, 1783; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany and ornithology.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni,Florence, May 6, 1785; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning correspondence with the academy of geography.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Sept. 20, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, Oct. 29, 1786; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a thermometer and barometer.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 1, 1786; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany and the museum of natural history.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 17, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 20, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces the Swedish consul in Tunis, Tulin.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 11, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Scientific news.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 11, 1787; B F113; 9x7-3/4; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning science.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 25, 1787; B F113; 9x7-3/4; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a shipment from the Near East.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, July 2, 1787; B F113; 9x7-3/4; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a ship and all that was quarantined in it.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 14, 1787; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 9p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning scientific subjects, especially mineralogy and botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 5, 1787; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 5p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning scientific subjects, especially botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 4, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 4, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning an antique vase.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 15, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 7p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for works on Malattia-Sciatica.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 18, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the shipment of a parcel marked F.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 14, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Zootechnics.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 7, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications of the French academies.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 11, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning scientific research.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, July 25, 1788; B F113; 12x8-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning mineralogy.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 5, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning botany and mineralogy.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 6, 1788; B F113; 12-1/4x8-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommends Vincenzo Gagliano and presends his work.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 26, 1788; B F113; 9-1/4x7-3/4; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the address of works for Fabroni.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 24, 1789; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication. General news.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Aug. 17, 1789; B F113; 9x7; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Gives detailed description of an event.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 3, 1789; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Mariti, Gio[vanni], 1736-1806.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning coal.
  - Letter to Gan Fabbroni, Florence, May, 1783; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Mascagni, Paolo, 1755-1815.
    Siena, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publication of Fontana.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Aug. 23, 1789; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Mascagni, Paolo, 1755-1815.
    Siena, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the publications of the Accademia delle scienze di Siena.
  - Letter to Abbé Felice Fontana,Florence, April 2, 1784; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Mascagni, Paolo, 1755-1815.
    Siena, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning medicine.
  - Letter to [Leopoldo Pelli Fabroni], June 14, 1862; B F113; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Matteucci, C[arlo], 1811-1868.
    A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Leopoldo Pelli] Fabbroni [sic], Dec. 19, 1863; B F113; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Matteucci, C[arlo], 1811-1868.
    A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Leopoldo Pelli Fabbroni [sic] Florence, July 13, 1847; B F113; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Matteucci, Carlo, 1811-1868.
    A.L.S. 2p.,end.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Dec. 21, 1795; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Mazzei, [Filippo], 1730-1816.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Questions concerning the printer.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, April, 1781; B F113; 7-1/4x5; Mazzei, [Signora Marie Hautefeuille Martin d.1788.
    ]. A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. ( see Fabroni papers.) Asks for passage home.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic]., B F113; 7x4-1/2; Mazzei, [Signora Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot dine with him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 22, 1781; B F113; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Mazzei, [Signora] P [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning her husband.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, Aug. 7, 1780; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks aid since her husband will not help her.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, Nov., 1781; B F113; 7-1/2x8-1/2; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    ]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his goodness to her.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, 1781?; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    ]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes he continues to send her aid.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Jan., 1782; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his favors and wants information of Filippo Mazzei.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 15, 1782; B F113; 9x7; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], -1788.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for all his favors and good-bye letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, 1780; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], d.1788.
    ]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes they will remain friends. Family difficulties.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, 1780?; B F113; 8-1/2x6; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], d.1788.
    ]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers News of her husband.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic, March, 1781?; B F113; 7x4-3/4; Mazzei, [Signora] Petronille [Marie Hautefeuille Martin], d.1788.
    ]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Business affairs.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 18, 1816; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Mazzei, Bettina
    Pisa, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Her unhappy situation. Concerning her father.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 20, 1816; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Mazzei, Bettina
    Pisa, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Her unhappy life. Death of her father.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 21, 1781; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; Mazzei, F[ilippo], 1730-1816.
    Leghorn, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his wife's affairs.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 25, 1773; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Jefferson awaits him. Asks him to prepare flowers and vegetables to bring with him to America, with new music, etc.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 10, 1774; B F113.m; 8-3/4x7; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Awaits him in America. Tells him to bring gun, violins, cards, etc; especially music. Jefferson awaits him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 6, 1774; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Advice for the Grand Duke's cabinet. Directions on how to prepare plants for trip to America. Asks for plants, tools, clothes, etc.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 20, 1774; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Orders supplies, music, etc. Enjoins secrecy to lull English suspicions.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 7, 1775; B F113.m; 9x7-1/2; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommends a better boat for the trip to America. Orders seeds, paper, etc. Items for the Cabinet of the Grand Duke.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 30, 1775; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Doctors are welcome in America. Has arranged for Fabroni's future as teacher of music. Music. Refers to Jefferson and Adams. Plans to settle in America.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 30, 1775; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Virginia, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Capt.Woodford "a Virginia gentleman," and hopes he will show him Florence. Business.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 30, 1781; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Directions for his wife's trip from Florence to Pisa.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 16, 1792; B F113.m; 7x5-3/4; Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.